migrationpolicy.org 2004-04-02

# MPI | About MPI | Privacy Policy

**PRIVACY POLICY FOR THE MIGRATION POLICY INSTITUTE**  
www.migrationpolicy.org 

Commitment to Privacy

The Migration Policy Institute ("MPI") respects the privacy of every individual who uses this website. This Privacy Policy outlines the information MPI will collect and how we will use that information. By using our website, you signify that you agree with the terms of our current Privacy Policy as posted in this area of the website. If you do not agree with any term in the Privacy Policy, please do not use this website. 

Personally Identifiable Information 

When you visit www.migrationpolicy.org, we will not collect any personally identifiable information about you (such as your name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. 

Some of our interactive pages may invite visitors to submit names or e-mail addresses in order to join a mailing list or submit comments. If you opt not to provide us with this information, no material consequences will result, although you may be unable to receive certain information sent out electronically by MPI. Parties wishing to join the mailing list or submit a comment or question are required to provide MPI with a variety of necessary and personally identifiable information, such as name, address, phone number, and e-mail address. 

Use of Personally Identifiable Information

MPI may store and process your personally identifiable information to better understand your needs and improve our website, and we may use your personally identifiable information to contact you. For example, at your request, we may send you event invitations, policy briefs, news updates, or other notices. In addition, we may use your information in order to respond to your comments or requests for information. 

MPI does not sell, rent, loan, trade or lease any of your personally identifiable information collected at our website to any outside entity. However, nothing in the Privacy Statement shall be deemed to prohibit MPI from disclosing your identity if MPI is required to do so by law. 

Security

We will take reasonable steps to keep all information as secure as possible against unauthorized access and use. All information will be protected by our security measures, which are periodically reviewed. 

Non-Personally Identifiable Information Collected Automatically

In some cases, we may collect information about you that is not personally identifiable. We may use computer technology in order to broadly track your movement on this website. This information tells us how you use this website and it allows us to tailor our website to better meet your needs. MPI makes no attempt to link this non-personal information with the individuals who browse this site. 

Terms of Use

While we have worked diligently to provide you with accurate and updated information on this website, we cannot be absolutely certain that everything on this website is free of errors or omissions. Therefore, we will not be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, consequential or punitive damages arising out of your access to or use of this website. Under no circumstance will MPI be liable for any loss or damage caused by your reliance on information obtained through this website. It is your responsibility to evaluate the accuracy, completeness or usefulness of any content available through this website. 

Links to Other Websites

Our website contains a link to [www.migrationinformation.org](http://www.migrationinformation.org/), a website run by MPI. This website is designed to provide you with accurate, updated migration data from around the world. MPI strives to make the information on www.migrationinformation.org as accurate as the information we present on this website. 

In addition, our website may contain other links to other websites for your convenience in locating related information and services. We are not responsible for and do not maintain these other sites, and have no control over the content, accuracy or opinions expressed in such websites. Furthermore, MPI has not investigated, monitored or checked the accuracy or completeness of any such website. Please note that the inclusion of any linked website does not imply approval or endorsement of the linked website by MPI. 

Accordingly, MPI expressly disclaims any responsibility for the content of these other websites, the accuracy of the information on these websites or the quality of products or services provided by the organizations that maintain them. The existence of such links should not be construed as a recommendation, endorsement, approval or verification by MPI of any content available on third party sites. MPI reserves the right to require written consent for, or request the removal of, any links to our website. 

No Liability for Acts of Third Parties

Although MPI will use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, transmissions made by means of the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure. MPI will have no liability for disclosure of information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. In addition, MPI will release specific information about you to comply with any valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute or court order. We also will release specific information in special cases, such as if there is an attempted breach of security or a physical threat to you or others. 

Contacting Us Regarding Your Personally Identifiable Information

If you have submitted personally identifiable information through this website, or if someone else has submitted your personally identifiable information through this website, and you would like to have that information deleted from our database, please contact us at the below address. We then will use reasonable efforts to remove your personally identifiable information from our files, unless we are entitled to retain it pursuant to an agreement that you have entered into with MPI. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us using the information below. 

Ana Claros  
202-266-1940  

Changes to Privacy Policy

Because of changes in Internet technology and practices, this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Please consult this portion of MPI's website to view important changes to the Privacy Policy as they occur. By using the website after MPI posts any changes to this Privacy Policy, you agree to accept those changes, whether or not you have reviewed them, and such acceptance shall be deemed legally conclusive. If at any time you choose not to accept the terms of this Privacy Policy, you will not use this website. 

Acceptance of Terms

By using this website, you have agreed to and accepted MPI's Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use this website.
